

Eric YU (914)-319-8132 ericyu3@illinois.edu

SUMMARY

High-achieving student pursuing degrees in **physics** and **mathematics** with a minor in **computer science**. Two-plus years of experience as an undergraduate research assistant doing work in theoretical and computational astrophysics. Experienced in **developing and maintaining Python/Bash code** that efficiently process and analyze large datasets.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS AT URBANA-CHAMPAIGN

Aug. 2020 - May 2024

B.S in Physics and B.S. in Mathematics, minor in Computer Science

• Unweighted GPA: 3.98/4.00

HORACE GREELEY HIGH SCHOOL

June 2020

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA

· Magna cum laude

EXPERIENCE

NATIONAL CENTER FOR SUPERCOMPUTING APPLICATIONS

June 2023 - Present

UNDERGRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

• Development and parallelization of COCAL code that solves the initial value problem in numerical relativity for a rotating neutron-star/black-hole surrounded by a self-gravitating gaseous disk.

CENTER FOR THEORETICAL ASTROPHYSICS, UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS AT URBANA-CHAMPAIGN June 2021 - Present Undergraduate Research Assistant

- Led a team of 5 undergraduates to create 3D visualizations on supercomputers of neutron stars, black hole disks, and binary black holes using an internally developed, VisIt CLI-based code.
- Developed a set of Python/Bash/C++ scripts that extract and visualize gravitational waveforms from numerical relativity simulation data.
- Co-developed a set of Python scripts that can measure the proper circumference of black holes, neutron stars, and accretion disks in curved spacetime.
- Award-winning visualizations featured in 3 Phys. Rev. D articles and CASC 2023.

AWARDS AND HONORS __

OFFICE OF UNDERGRADUATE RESEARCH SUPPORT GRANT (\$1750)

RALPH O. SIMMONS UNDERGRADUATE RESEARCH SCHOLARSHIP (\$3000)

LORELLA M. JONES SUMMER RESEARCH AWARD (\$3000)

May 2021

COURSEWORK _

PHYSICS Classical Mechanics | Electricity & Magnetism | Quantum Mechanics

Statistical Mechanics (FA'23) | General Relativity (FA'23)

MATHEMATICS Statistics & Probability | Multivariable Calculus | Differential Equations

Linear Algebra | Differential Geometry | Abstract Algebra (FA'23) | Real Analysis (FA'23)

COMPUTER SCIENCE Data Structures | Machine Learning | Numerical Analysis

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING Experienced: Python | Bash Familiar: C++ | Java

LIBRARIES NumPy | Matplotplib | SciPy | PyTorch